<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi! I'm Konrad</title><link>https://konradmalik.com/</link><description>Recent content on Hi! I'm Konrad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 22:29:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://konradmalik.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git Autosquashing</title><link>https://konradmalik.com/posts/2023/03/git-autosquashing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 22:29:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://konradmalik.com/posts/2023/03/git-autosquashing/</guid><description>Git Commits Autosquashing A quick tip this time.
Sometimes you stumble on that one blog post that dramatically improves your life. Autosquashing Git Commits post from thoughtbot was such an improvement for me recently.
The problem You&amp;rsquo;re working on a merge request. You&amp;rsquo;re committing directly to your side project repo. You&amp;rsquo;re committing your code as fast as you think. You&amp;rsquo;re in &amp;ldquo;the flow&amp;rdquo;.
Suddenly you realize - in the commit you&amp;rsquo;ve just pushed, there is a bug/typo/simple mistake, whatever.</description></item><item><title>sops-nix: simple secrets management for Nix</title><link>https://konradmalik.com/posts/2023/02/sops-nix-simple-secrets-management-for-nix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 22:57:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://konradmalik.com/posts/2023/02/sops-nix-simple-secrets-management-for-nix/</guid><description>Secrets in git There are many ways to manage secrets in git repositories. Some examples in no particular order:
git-crypt sops a separate private repo added as a submodule to the main one Each with its advantages and disadvantages, but all get the job done.
When I transitioned my dotfiles to Nix flakes, I looked for a way to not only manage secrets in git but for something that would also allow me to treat secrets as a part of my Nix config, including the declarative part.</description></item><item><title>Hello world</title><link>https://konradmalik.com/posts/2023/02/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 21:31:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://konradmalik.com/posts/2023/02/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello there!
I&amp;rsquo;m Konrad, and the first of my New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions was to resurrect and refresh my personal page.
Since this is now done, we can go straight into my second resolution which is: start a blog.
Why? Even though I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on publishing/promoting this anywhere (which means barely anyone will ever read this), I believe that there is something in translating your ideas, problems, and their solutions, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>